Kim Rasmussen

Elmhurst, IL · 248 701-8061 · Kim.rasmussen14@gmail.com · https://kimrass14.github.io/portfolio/

Software Engineer

My dedication to produce high quality work brings thoughtfulness at every stage. I'm driven to create work that is purposeful and creates efficiency for users without sacrificing on value. Years of forensic accounting experience results in detailed analyses that make a difference.

SKILLS

CSS, HTML, JavaScript, ¡Query, React, Express, Mongo, Mongoose, Ruby on Rails, SQL, GitHub

EXPERIENCE

General Assembly, Software Engineering Immersive Program, remote Aug 2020 - Nov 2020 Applied developer skills in MVC framework to group and individual projects during a 500-hour course. Projects include, but not limited to:

- Portfolio Built a website about myself as a developer to include projects I worked on and to showcase my skills in CSS (including grid and flexbox), HTML, JavaScript and jQuery to pull API from a google sheet of project data.
- the.Learn An app where users can take multiple choice quizzes on certain subjects as well as create their own by inputting custom categories and questions. The results of questions correct by category are displayed in a dynamic d3 bubble chart. Technologies used were React, d3, SCSS, Ruby on Rails. Full CRUD functionality.
- Pause An app for users to maintain a wishlist of self care activities. Full CRUD functionality with auth using React, Express, Mongo and Node.js. This was a group project built in a week. My primary responsibility was for the front end functionality in React.

Ernst & Young LLP, Fraud and Integrity Services Senior Manager, Chicago, IL Apr 2012 - Jun 2020

- Conducted and managed over XX bribery and corruption investigations and risk assessments for US based clients in varying industries.
- This includes managing an FCPA investigation into potential improper payments made to
 government officials in Thailand for a Fortune 100 US based client. Oversaw team that reviewed
 over 100K electronic documents, transaction testing, project file review. Performed detailed
 disgorgement calculation and supported external counsel with witness interviews. Supported
 client in their response to the SEC and DOJ investigation.
- Conducted and managed over XX financial misstatement investigations.
- This includes managing an investigation into millions of dollars of alleged inflated asset valuations. Performed quality review of team's analyses of assets, transactions, financial statement impact. Supported external counsel in conducting witness interviews.

Ernst & Young LLP Financial Statement Auditor Senior, Detroit, MI Sep 2009 - Mar 2012

• Conducted period end financial statement audit of \$XM division of a Fortune 100 automotive supplier. Completed detailed review of material asset, liability and equity accounts to assess reasonableness and adherence to Generally Accepted Accounting Principles.

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Immersive Student, General Assembly, remote

Bachelor of Arts in Accounting, Michigan State University, East Lansing, MI,

Masters in Science in Accounting, Michigan State University, East Lansing, MI,

Aug 2

Aug 2020 - Nov 2020 Aug 2004 - May 2008 Aug 2008 - May 2009